A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Population Program, Program Staff Files FA646
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, International Division, Population Program, Program Staff Files
1953-1978
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA646
7.64 Cubic Feet 6 cubic foot boxes and 1 document box.
Separated Materials
Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
Arranged in 5 series:
1. Vertical Files.
2. Program Review.
3. Meetings and Conferences.
4. Lake Como Conference.
5. Overseas Development (OD) Self Study.
Scope and Contents
Primarily contains meeting and conference files as well as documentaiton of studies and program planning and reviews.
Conditions Governing Access
Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
- Vertical Files, 1959-1978; I
  - Australia -- Walters, Dr. W.A.W. (Monash University), 1974 (Box 1)
  - Belgium -- Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Belgium -- General, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Britain -- Correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 1)
  - Britain -- Report, "Reproductive Biology Research and Contraceptive Development in the United Kingdom", 1975 February (Box 1)
  - Canada -- Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Canada -- Data, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Argentina, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Central America, 1963-1966 (Box 1)
  - Chile, 1964-1966 (Box 1)
  - Colombia, 1962-1966 (Box 1)
  - Mexico, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Peru, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Uruguay -- General, 1963-1965 (Box 1)
  - Venezuela, 1964-1966 (Box 1)
  - Middle East and Africa -- General Activities, 1962-1966 (Box 1)
  - Algeria, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Iran, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Morocco, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Tunisia, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Turkey, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - United Arab Republic (U.A.R.) (Egypt), 1966 (Box 1)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Urban League, 1966 (Box 1)
  - CELADE (United Nations Latin American Demographic Centre), 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Organization of American States (OAS), 1965 (Box 1)
  - Pan American Health Organization (PAHO), 1964-1966 (Box 1)
  - India -- Demography, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - India -- Ford Foundation -- Condom Manufacturing Consultants, 1964 (Box 2)
  - India -- Family Planning, 1962-1966 (Box 2)
  - India -- Ford Foundation -- Research in Reproductive Biology, 1961-1965 (Box 2)
  - American Public Health Association, 1965 (Box 2)
  - United States (US) -- "M" and "N" -- General, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Nigeria, 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - Southeast Asia -- Ford Foundation Development Plan -- Population Survey, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Southeast Asia -- General, 1962-1963 (Box 2)
  - Indonesia, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Philippines -- Ford Foundation Activities, 1962-1964 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
  - Egypt -- Correspondence, 1977 (Box 2)
  - India -- Family Planning -- Medical Aspects -- Research in Reproductive Biology, 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - India -- Consultants and Staff Papers, 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - India -- Government Programs, 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - Pakistan, 1959-1964 (Box 2)
  - Malaysia (except Singapore), 1966 (Box 2)
- Program Review, 1968-1978; II
  - Future Program Planning Projects -- Miscellaneous Papers, 1975-1976 (Box 3)
  - International Rice Research Institute -- Program Review, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Project Cornelius -- Cases and Notes on the Corn Industry in the Philippines, 1970 May (Box 3)
  - Gwatkin, Davidson R., 1976-1978 (Box 3)
  - Research Program Review, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Rural Development DAP, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Germain, Adrienne, 1976-1978 (Box 3)
  - Ford Foundation Fellowship Survey, 1968-1970 (Box 3)
  - Reproductive Biology Meeting, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Reproductive Biology Review, 1972 January 6-7 (Box 3)
- Meetings and Conferences, 1953-1977; III
  - Aspen Institute Conference, 1965 June 16-22 (Box 4)
  - Ford Foundation -- Meetings and Conferences, 1953-1966 (Box 4)
  - Population Council -- Strategy and Tactics Meeting, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Johns Hopkins International Conference on Population, May 1964 (Box 4)
  - Conferences -- NIH/AAAS -- Behavioral Sciences and Family Planning, 1967 June 7-9 (Box 4)
  - First and Second PAHO (Pan American Health Organization) Conference on Population Dynamics -- Washington, 1965 January 7 (Box 4)
  - Third Population Conference -- Bellagio, Italy, 1973 May 10 (Box 4)
  - Bellagio IV Conference -- Denmark, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Rockefeller Foundation -- Population Seminar -- Stock-Taking and Where Things Stand, 1975 July 17-18 (Box 4)
  - Rockefeller Foundation -- Population Seminar -- Path-Locating: Where to Go from Here, 1975 July 17-18 (Box 4)
  - Rockefeller Foundation -- Population Seminar, 1975 July 17-18 (Box 4)
  - Rockeller Foundation -- Meeting Re: Collaboration in Support of ICCR, 1977 August 15 (Box 4)
  - Bellagio IV -- Denmark -- Papers, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Bellagio IV -- Denmark -- Documents, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Bellagio IV -- Denmark, 1977 (Box 4)
- Lake Como Conference, 1968; IV
  Sound recordings
  - Session I, 1968 April 8 (Box 5)
  - Session II, 1968 April 8 (Box 5)
  - Session III, 1968 April 8 (Box 5)
  - Session IV, 1968 April 9 (Box 5)
  - Session V, 1968 April 9 (Box 5)
  - Session VI, 1968 April 9 (Box 5)
  - Session VII, 1968 April 10 (Box 5)
  - Session VIII, 1968 April 10 (Box 5)
  - Session X, 1968 April 11 (Box 5)
  - Session XI, 1968 April 11 (Box 5)
  - Ford Foundation Population Consultants Conference -- Lake Como: Audio Tapes, 1968 (Box 6)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Magnetic audio tape
    - Ford Foundation Population Consultants Conference -- Lake Como: Day 1, 1968 April 8; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6, Reel AV 15701)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Access copy available.
    - Ford Foundation Population Consultants Conference -- Lake Como: Day 2, 1968 April 9; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6, Reel AV 15702)
    - Ford Foundation Population Consultants Conference -- Lake Como: Day 3, 1968 April 10; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6, Reel AV 15703)
    - Ford Foundation Population Consultants Conference -- Lake Como: Day 4, 1968 April 11; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6, Reel AV 15704)
    - Ford Foundation Population Consultants Conference -- Lake Como: Day 1, Session 1 - Preparing the Way for a Nationwide Family Planning Program, 1968 April 8; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6, Reel AV 15705)
    - Ford Foundation Population Consultants Conference -- Lake Como: Day 1, Session 2 - National Family Planning Programs: Organization and Adminisration, 1968 April 8; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6, Reel AV 15706)
    - Ford Foundation Population Consultants Conference -- Lake Como: Day 1, Session 3 - Program Organization and Administration continued, 1968 April 8; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6, Reel AV 15707)
    - Ford Foundation Population Consultants Conference -- Lake Como: Day 2, Session 4 - Contraceptive Technology, 1968 April 9; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6, Reel AV 15708)
    - Ford Foundation Population Consultants Conference -- Lake Como: Day 2, Session 5 - Training for Family Planning Personnel, 1968 April 9; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6, Reel AV 15709)
    - Ford Foundation Population Consultants Conference -- Lake Como: Day 2, Session 6 - Mass Media and Educational Programs, 1968 April 9; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6, Reel AV 15710)
    - Ford Foundation Population Consultants Conference -- Lake Como: Day 3, Session 7 Evaluation Techniques for Assessing Increases in Birth Conrol Practice and the Impact on the Birth Rate, 1968 April 10; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6, Reel AV 15711)
    - Ford Foundation Population Consultants Conference -- Lake Como: Day 3, Session 8 - Overall Assessment of Family Planning in Developing World, 1968 April 10; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6, Reel AV 15712)
    - Ford Foundation Population Consultants Conference -- Lake Como: Day 3, Session 9 - Continuation of previous sessions, 1968 April 10; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6, Reel AV 15713)
    - Ford Foundation Population Consultants Conference -- Lake Como: Day 4, Session 10 - Foundation Policy with Reference to Population Work, 1968 April 11; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6, Reel AV 15714)
    - Ford Foundation Population Consultants Conference -- Lake Como: Day 4, Session 11 - Foundation Policy with Reference to Population Work, 1968 April 11; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6, Reel AV 15715)
  - Ford Foundation Population Consultants Conference -- Lake Como: Conference Transcripts, 1968; document box (Box 7)
    - Ford Foundation Population Consultants Conference -- Lake Como -- Transcript, 1968 April 8 (Box 7)
    - Ford Foundation Population Consultants Conference -- Lake Como -- Transcript, 1968 April 9 (Box 7)
    - Ford Foundation Population Consultants Conference -- Lake Como -- Transcript, 1968 April 10 (Box 7)
    - Ford Foundation Population Consultants Conference -- Lake Como -- Transcript, 1968 April 11 (Box 7)
- Overseas Development (OD) Self Study, 1966-1971; V
  - Peru, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Venezuela, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Brazil, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Colombia, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Central America, 1966 (Box 5)
  - General, 1966-1971 (Box 5)
  - Argentina, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Brazil #2, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Chile, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Mexico, 1966 (Box 5)